Italians of New London Oral History Collection
© 2008 University of Connecticut
Italians of New London Oral History Collection.
1997-1998.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Fischer, Jerome.
3.3 linear feet.
The Italians of New London Oral History Project was conducted by Jerome Fischer, director of the Jewish Federation of Eastern Connecticut, based in New London.
MSS20010118
History
The Italians of New London Oral History Project was conducted by Jerome Fischer, director of the Jewish Federation of Eastern Connecticut, based in New London, CT.
Scope and Content
The collection contains video tape recordings of individuals of Italian descent living in the New London, Connecticut, area.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of oral histories and materials pertaining to ethnic groups in Connecticut. Specific collections include: the Center for Oral History Interviews, Peoples of Connecticut Project, Estonian, Latvian, Lithuanian Alliance of Connecticut Records, Bisaillon Collection Of French Canadians in Connecticut Collection and the WPA Survey Records. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Italian Americans--Connecticut--New London--History.; New London (Conn.)--Emmigration and immigration--History.; New London (Conn.) Ethnic relations History.
Document Types:
Videocassettes.
Occupations:
Director of the Jewish Federation of Eastern Connecticut.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The videocassettes were donated by Mr. Fischer in 2001.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Collection, 1997-1998
  - Argento, Angelo & Rosario; Scenes from Gardens of Angelo Argento, Leonard Rocco & Morris Macione [Dodd Video 141], New London, CT, 1998 (Box 1:, Othertype 1)
  - Basilica, Anthony, Pt. 1 [Dodd Video 142], New London, CT, 1998 (Box 1:, Othertype 2)
  - Basilica, Anthony, Pt. 2 [Dodd Video 142], New London, CT, 1998 (Box 1:, Othertype 3)
  - Castanza, Joseph [Dodd Video 143], Waterford, CT, 1997 February 12 (Box 1:, Othertype 4)
  - Cavasino, Gaspare & Elinor (Orazi) [Dodd Video 144], New London, CT, 1997 (Box 1:, Othertype 5)
  - Coman, Mary (Dandona) [Dodd Video 145], New London, CT, 1997 July 28 (Box 1:, Othertype 6)
  - DiMaggio, Thomas F. & Mary (Romano) [Dodd Video 146], 1998 January 26 (Box 1:, Othertype 7)
  - Donatello, Carl A., Pt. 1 [Dodd Video 147], Waterford, CT, 1997 (Box 1:, Othertype 8)
  - Donatello, Carl A., Pt. 2 [Dodd Video 147], Waterford, CT, 1997 (Box 1:, Othertype 9)
  - Ferro, Nicholas & Margaret (Ferro) Cataldi [Dodd Video 148], New London, 1998 February 26 (Box 1:, Othertype 10)
  - Filippetti, Kathleen (Gaudet) & Gaetano, Wanda (Filippetti) [Dodd Video 149], Groton, CT, 1997 (Box 1:, Othertype 11)
  - Frausini, Alan & Rita (Ferri)& Inez (Ciofi) & Vilma (Gramolini) [Dodd Video 150], Montville, CT, 1998 (Box 1:, Othertype 12)
  - Frausini, Victor Jr. & Alan [Dodd Video 151], Montville, CT, 1998 July 16 (Box 1:, Othertype 13)
  - Gigliotti, Rosario “Russ” [Dodd Video 152], East Lyme, CT, 1997, September 16 (Box 2:, Othertype 14)
  - Londregan, Francis “Frank” [Dodd Video 153], New London, CT, 1998 August 21 (Box 2:, Othertype 15)
  - Longo, Vincent & Esposito, Louis & Folino, Pasquale [Dodd Video 154], New London, CT, 1998 (Box 2:, Othertype 16)
  - Macione, Morris [Dodd Video 155], New London, CT, 1998 January 20 (Box 2:, Othertype 17)
  - Mercuri, Luigi & Teresa (Mercuri) Walsh [Dodd Video 156], New London, CT, 1997 (Box 2:, Othertype 18)
  - Modugno, Nichole (Pescatello) Londregan [Dodd Video 157], New London, CT, 1998 August 21 (Box 2:, Othertype 19)
  - Orsini, A. Matt & Emma (Mondelci) [Dodd Video 158], New London, CT, 1998 February 15 (Box 2:, Othertype 20)
  - Perrone, Carmelo [Dodd Video 159], Waterford, CT, 1998 July 9 (Box 2:, Othertype 21)
  - Rocco, Leonard A. [Dodd Video 160], New London, CT, 1998 September 8 (Box 2:, Othertype 22)
  - Santaniello, Angelo [Dodd Video 161], New London, CT, 1998 (Box 2:, Othertype 23)
  - Scarpa, Peter [Dodd Video 162], New London, CT, 1998 September 15 (Box 2:, Othertype 24)
  - Serluca, Anthony & Ferdinand [Dodd Video 163], New London, CT, 1998 May 12 (Box 2:, Othertype 25)
  - Tranchida, Lucy (Fazzini) & Paul [Dodd Video 164], Groton, CT, 1997 August 7 (Box 2:, Othertype 26)
  - Tranchida, Paul [Dodd Video 165], Groton, CT, 1997 August 7 (Box 3:, Othertype 27)
  - Valentini, Aldo [Dodd Video 166], New London, CT, 1998 (Box 3:, Othertype 28)
  - Carnival Festival held by New London, CT, “Sons of Italy Lodge” [Dodd Video 167], Groton, CT, 1998 (Box 3:, Othertype 29)
  - Interview of Women Cooking in Morning at Italian Dramatic Club; New London, CT; Interview of Iovine, Maria (Panucci) & Yost, Catherine (Miglore) [Dodd Video 168], New London, CT, 1997-1998 (Box 3:, Othertype 30)
  - Interview of Italian Dramatic Club Dinner's Male Cooks & Interview of Individuals Present & Old Photos on Bulletin Board [Dodd Video 169], New London, CT, 1998 (Box 3:, Othertype 31)
  - New London Development Corporation Meeting with President Claire Gaudiani Presiding [Dodd Video 170], New London, CT, 1998 April 27 (Box 3:, Othertype 32)
  - Various Video Clips (Uncaptioned); Assumption Day, St. Mary's Church - 1998; C. Perrone's Guided Tour; Italian Soc. Club Homes; Homes Built by Italians; Monuments Erected by Italians [Dodd Video 171], New London & Waterford, CT, 1998 (compiled) (Box 3:, Othertype 33)
  - Various Still Photos (Uncaptioned) & Maps Pertinent to New London, CT & Its Italian Community [Dodd Video 172], 1998 (compiled) (Box 3:, Othertype 34)
  - “The Italians of New London, A Film by Jerry Fischer” [Dodd Video 173], 1998 (Box 3:, Othertype 35)
  - Original format (Super VHS and Beta) tapes (Box 4-5)